有许多关于骑士精神的故事
There are many stories of chivalry
讲述英勇的骑士救出身陷危险的少女
where the heroic knight saves the damsel in distress.
但这个故事不一样
This is not one of them.
它在那里
There it is.
列阵!
Form up!
去干掉这头野兽
Let's kill the beast.
为荣耀而战!
For glory! Hyah!
保持警惕
Be on guard.
排成一行!
Form the line!
坚守阵地!
Hold!
几个世纪后❫
在遥远的土地上❫
只找到最后一根了
The last I could find.
你按父亲的要求 把挂毯拿去镇上了吗?
Did you take the tapestries into town like Father asked?
今早去了
This morning.
我们应该把皮草和布帘都带去
We should take the furs too, and the drapes.
别拿布帘!
Not the drapes!
反正你讨厌在房间挂那个图案的布帘
You hate that pattern in your room anyway.
布帘是有用的
They serve a purpose.
弗洛丽亚 大家都在挨冻
Floria, our people are freezing.
饿肚子
And starving.
谁会如此深入北境?
Who'd come this far north?
伊洛蒂 他们为什么要走?
Elodie, why are they leaving?
他们在这一无所有了 弗洛丽亚
There's nothing left for them here, Floria.
我还没吃够 拜托 我饿坏了
I don't have enough. Please, I'm hungry.
想领食物就排队!
For food, join the line!
站到一边
Keep to one side.
我要饿死了
I'm starving.
那好吧
All right then.
松手! 这是我的!
Get off! It's mine!
- 嘿! 把食物还给我  - 放开我 老汉!
- Hey! Give me back my food. - Get off of me, old man!
你吃得够多了!
You've had enough!
跟你姐姐一起吃 去吧
Share this with your sister. Go on.
- 你看清是谁了吗?  - 生面孔 小姐
- Could you see who it was? - A stranger, my lady.
他们想带走多少木头都可以
They may take whatever wood they can carry.
- 遵命  - 来吧 弗洛丽亚
- I'll see to it. - Come on, Flor.
- 继续走  - 好
- Move on. - Yes.
- 排队  - 快给我
- Get in line. - Give it to me.
我想先见见她
I want to meet her first.
父亲?
Father?
你一定是伊洛蒂
You must be Elodie.
没错
I am.
她还行
She will do.
静候你们的佳音
We await your decision.
谢谢 殿下
Thank you, Your Holiness.
请走这边
Please, this way.
父亲 怎么回事?
Father, what's happening?
她是谁?
Who is that?
继母?
Stepmother?
怎么了嘛?
Well, what is it?
来自奥瑞亚女王
From the Queen of Aurea.
是来提亲的
A proposal.
天哪
Oh, my goodness.
- 我帮女儿找到了郎君  - 我看看
- I have made a match. - May I?
他是王子
He is a prince.
王子?
A prince?
我知道你像你母亲一样 一直盼望能出远门
I know you've always wished to travel, as did your mother.
去吧 去领略世界
Go. See the world.
这个男人拥有一支船队 和装满黄金的马车
This man, he has a fleet of ships, carriages full of gold.
这不是结婚的理由
That's no reason to marry.
我们要把握机会
We need this.
我们的粮仓空了
Our stores are empty.
我们熬不到融雪的那一天
We will not make it to the thaw.
你的子民需要你
Your people need you.
嘿
Hey.
这就是我们的职责
This is who we are.
过去左舷
Get to the port side.
左舷
Port side.
伊洛蒂 你怎么了?
Elodie, what's the matter?
没什么
Nothing.
父亲说 第一次去见
Father says it's natural to be nervous
新婚丈夫和他家人 觉得紧张很正常
about meeting your new husband and his family.
他们是陌生人
They're strangers.
父亲让我措手不及 以前我都没听说过奥瑞亚王国
I've never heard of the Kingdom of Aurea until Father sprang this on me.
小心绳索
Mind the lines.
你们疯了吗? 你们去那上面做什么?
Are you crazy? What are you two doing up there?
快下来
Come down here.
来吧
Come on.
你就打算这样去见王子吗?
This is how you want your prince to meet you?
惶恐不安 浑身冰凉
Scared, cold as a corpse.
冻得都流鼻涕了
Nose all drippy and wet.
这一路上我是怎么跟你们说的?
What have I been telling you this entire trip?
第一印象非常关键
First impressions are everything.
来 升起来
Come on, lift up.
瞧啊
Look at that.
我有好消息 姑娘们
I have good news, girls.
船长通知我 我们接近奥瑞亚海岸线了
The captain informs me we approach Aurea's coastline.
应该马上就到了
It should be any time now.
父亲
Father.
什么名堂?
What in the world?
好像...好像是...
Looks almost... almost like a--
一条龙
A dragon.
没事的
It's okay.
少女斗恶龙
我的天啊
Oh, my heavens.
真是华丽
It's magnificent.
大人 夫人 两位小姐
My lords, my ladies,
欢迎来到奥瑞亚王国
be welcome to the Kingdom of Aurea.
皇室正在祈祷
The royal family is at prayer,
但已派人去通报 说各位抵达了
but word has been sent of your arrival.
另外 各位的客房均已准备妥当
In the meantime, your rooms have been made ready.
请随我来
If you will follow me.
这是在做梦吧?
Is this a dream?
如果是的话 我能搬进梦乡再也不醒吗?
If so, can I move in and never wake up?
如果你想让这些人 认为我们配得上这里
If you want these people to think we belong here,
你就不能这么大惊小怪的
you can't act so easily impressed.
伊洛蒂 你怎么想?
What do you think, Ellie? Hmm?
我觉得这里的富裕程度 远超出我之前的想象
I think I had a rather limited definition of wealthy.
我希望这正合您意 小姐
I pray this is to your liking, my lady.
浴缸已经备好水
A bath has been drawn
膳食也呈上来了
and supper has been carried hence.
明天一早 我会来带您去
At first light, I shall return to convey you
觐见王子殿下
to meet His Royal Highness.
奥瑞亚王子亨利
Henry, Prince of Aurea.
弗洛丽亚 别到处乱摸
Floria, stop touching everything.
怎么了?
Is something wrong?
我只希望他是善良的人
I just hope he's kind.
- 知书达理  - 嗯
- And well-read. - Yeah.
帅气
Handsome.
我们给伊洛蒂留点私人空间吧
Let's all give Elodie some privacy.
她可以花点时间适应 我们也一样
She can use the time to settle in, as we all could.
确实是呢
Oh, indeed.
来吧
Come.
小姐
M'lady.
大家都在等着了
Everyone's waiting.
伊洛蒂?
Ellie?
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
我依然不敢相信 今后你就要住在这里了
I still can't believe you're going to live here from now on.
我也跟你一样
You and me both.
我一直在想 要是母亲还在世就好了
I keep thinking, if only Mother were alive,
我就能把所有这些事情告诉她
I could just talk to her about all of this.
或许你可以跟继母谈谈
Perhaps you could talk to Stepmother.
她人很好 虽然她有点...
She means well, even if she is a bit...
烦人?
Exhausting?
没事的 到时你就知道了
It'll be fine. You'll see.
你是伊洛蒂 你无所不能
You're Elodie. You can do anything.
你最大的优点是什么?
What is your greatest strength?
我从不撒谎 女王陛下
I always tell the truth, Your Majesty.
有人会觉得这是弱点
Some might call that a weakness.
你了解自己的内心吗?
Do you know your heart?
我相信我了解 女王陛下
I believe I do, Your Majesty.
你的内心在说什么?
And what is it telling you now?
此刻我的心跳得太响 我几乎听不清它在说什么 女王陛下
In truth, it is beating too loudly for me to hear much of anything, Your Majesty.
平身吧 伊洛蒂
Arise, Elodie.
我是亨利
I'm Henry.
很高兴终于见到你了 小姐
Very pleased to finally meet you, my lady.
我们都是
We all are.
我王儿所言未能表达我们的喜悦心情
My son understates our joy.
恕我直言
And if I may say so,
你比你父亲说的还要美
your father has understated your beauty.
其实我父亲说任何事 一向都言过其实 女王陛下
I've never known my father to understate much of anything, Your Majesty.
我看小姐说话还挺风趣
I see she arrives with some wit.
她就是这个样子 陛下
Should you want it or not, Your Majesty.
你一定是弗洛丽亚
And you must be Floria.
看来即便是艰难的环境 也能滋养出最美丽的花朵
It seems even a harsh clime can grow the fairest flowers.
我喜欢你们的城堡
I love your castle.
我真的很喜欢
I mean, I really love it.
非常喜欢...
Like, a lot...
女王陛下
Your Majesty.
就当这里是自己家就好 孩子
You are to make yourself at home, child.
我们几位长辈 有些诸如婚礼等琐事要商量
We elders have some trivial matters like weddings to attend to.
是的...
Yes...
您在信中提到了有些特别的事宜
Your correspondence made mention of some particulars
您希望当面商量
you wish to discuss in person.
- 我们二人可以私下商讨  - 好的
- The two of us can confer in private. - Yes.
没必要让你们年轻人感到无聊
It's nothing to bore our young people with.
他们还有更重要的事要做
They have a far more important task at hand.
他们得相互熟悉一下
They must get to know each other.
你有什么问题要问我吗?
Do you have any questions of me?
关于什么的问题?
Questions of what subject?
话题由你选
You may choose the subject.
你觉得我怎么样?
What do you think about me?
什么?
Pardon?
你看起来很不感兴趣 这是你的特权
Well, you seem disinterested at best, which is your prerogative,
但是我想知道 我因为内疚而同意的结婚对象
but I'd like to know if the person I'm being guilted into marrying
是不是真的喜欢我
truly likes me or not.
如果我的态度有所冒犯 我道歉 这不是我的本意
If my attitude offends you, I do apologize. It was not my intent.
但是 我并不知道 你是因为内疚才同意这样做的
However, I was unaware that, um, you were being guilted into anything.
我的家乡就像你母亲说的一样
The land where I come from is exactly how your mother explained.
艰苦而贫瘠
Harsh and barren.
这次联姻将会拯救我们的族人
This union will save us.
我已经接受了事实
I've made my peace with it.
为了我们族人的未来 我个人的幸福只是很小的代价
My happiness is a small price to pay for the future of my people.
有什么不对吗?
Is something wrong?
只是...
It's just...
在你来之前寄的信件里 你的语气不一样
In the letter you sent in advance of your arrival, you sounded different.
怎么不一样?
Different. In what way?
你在信里更加...
Far more, um...
文辞华丽
flowery.
或许是因为 大部分内容都是我继母口述的
Maybe that's because my stepmother dictated most of it
而那个心是我妹妹的主意
and my sister's idea was the heart...
那个心?
The heart.
我还以为是某种地方徽章呢
I thought it was some sort of provincial insignia.
这真是你画的?
You actually drew this?
慢着 这是一个迷宫 对吧?
Hold on. It's a maze, isn't it?
"我希望你会了解我的心"
"I hope you'll get to know my heart."
真是睿智
That is very clever.
弗洛丽亚小时候 我经常给她画
I used to make them for Floria when she was little.
- 我能再问你一个问题吗?  - 当然可以
- May I ask you another question? - Certainly.
他们总是紧跟着你吗?
Do they always follow you so closely?
这已经算是离得远了
This is them giving me space.
你肯定觉得心累
That must be tiring.
确实是的
It is, actually.
我看见马厩里有几匹马无人看管
I saw some horses being left unattended at the stables.
你会骑马?
Do you ride?
- 你是从哪学会这样骑马的?  - 我母亲教的
- Where did you learn to ride like that? - My mother.
现在往哪边走?
Which way now?
那就要看你想去看什么了
Well, depends on what you want to see.
什么都想看
Everything.
好吧
Very well.
在里面聊了什么?
What happened in there?
快说呀
Speak already.
- 还举行婚礼吗?  - 是的
- Is the wedding still on? - Aye.
彩礼你谈到好价格了吗?
You settled on a fair bride price?
金子多到我无法想象
More gold than I could ever imagine.
那你为什么还这副表情?
Then why do you look so?
没什么 我没事
No, it's nothing. I'm fine.
快告诉我 你没乱说话丢我们的脸吧?
Tell me, you didn't say anything to embarrass us.
没有 我没乱说
No, I did not.
因为我们两家人必须要和睦相处
Because it's very important that our two families get along.
不光是为了伊洛蒂 也是为了我们
Not only for Elodie's sake, but for ours.
我说了没事! 没出问题
I said, nothing! Nothing's wrong.
我昨天看见高山上有东西
I saw something, high on the mountain last night.
有一些火把
Torches.
你看到了?
You saw that?
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
那是在举行古老的仪式
It was an ancient ceremony.
或者说是三个仪式之一
Or rather, one of three.
我们皇室非常重视这种仪式
They're very significant to my family.
其实是为了整个王国好 仪式...
For our whole kingdom, really. They, um...
是用来向祖先表达敬意的
They honor our ancestors.
所以我母亲特意 选了这些日子为我们举办婚礼
That's why my mother chose these dates for our wedding.
这太美了
It is quite beautiful.
对 我想是的
Yes, I suppose.
主要是我没有别的景色跟它做比较
I really don't have anything else to compare it to.
我能跟你吐露心声吗?
May I confide in you something?
好的
Yes.
我最大的愿望是去周游世界
My greatest wish is to go see the world.
真的动身去见识一下 你明白吗?
Really set out and see it, you know?
其实我明白
I do, actually.
这是我一生的梦想
It's my life's dream.
从我记事开始 我就渴望去探索遥远的大地
For as long as I can remember, I've longed to explore the distant lands.
那些在书里才能看到的地方
The ones you only read about.
或许有一天我们可以一起去
Perhaps, one day, we will.
或许吧
Perhaps.
这一片区域是橙色的
And the orange in this area.
一切都很美 女王陛下
Everything's so beautiful, Your Majesty.
我很高兴能合你意
Well, I'm glad you approve.
很高雅
Very elegant.
您的品位真是无可挑剔
You have impeccable taste.
所有东西都很精致
Everything is just so exquisite.
抱歉 有什么需要帮忙的吗?
I'm sorry, is there something I can help you with?
我想着我们或许可以熟络一点
I just thought we might become better acquainted,
眼看我们就要成为一家人了
seeing as we're about to be family.
这桩婚事肯定令你非常激动
Ah, this must be very exciting for you.
你的父亲是绳索匠 对吧?
Your father was a rope maker, was he not?
是城里最好的
The finest in the city.
现在你们来了这里 爬到了这么高的位置
And here you are. You've climbed so high.
即便如此 人还是不能忘了自己的位置
Still, one mustn't forget one's station.
也不要过分看重这桩婚事
Nor place undue import
毕竟只是一场利益交换而已
on what is ultimately a transaction born of necessity.
"利益"?
"Necessity"?
你的家庭需要钱
Well, your family needs money.
而我们皇室需要新娘
My family needs a bride.
我们最不需要的就是再来一群亲戚
What we don't need is more family.
我希望亨利和埃洛伊丝百年好合
I wish all the best for Henry and Eloise.
- 我只是...  - 伊洛蒂
- I merely-- - Elodie.
什么?
Pardon?
我的继女 她叫伊洛蒂
My stepdaughter. Her name is Elodie.
我就是这么说的
That's what I said.
祝你日安 百福特夫人
Good day, Lady Bayford.
真是完美
It's perfect.
这里的一切都很完美
Everything in here is so perfect.
继母
Stepmother.
有什么事吗?
Is something the matter?
伊洛蒂
Elodie,
我知道我们一直以来不算亲密
I know we haven't always been close,
但是现在你要听我说
but I need you to listen to me now.
这场婚礼...不该办
This wedding... is a mistake.
什么?
What?
我没听明白
I don't understand.
我不信任这些人
These people, I don't trust them.
这种感觉很难解释 但是当妈的就是感觉得到
It's hard to explain, but a mother knows these things.
昨天你还被这个地方迷住了呢
Only yesterday, you were enamored by this place.
弗洛丽亚
Floria.
是我搞错了
I was wrong.
虽然他们是皇室 但这不代表他们就是好人
They may be royalty, but that doesn't make them good people.
嗯...
Well...
- 父亲怎么想?  - 他不愿意多说
- What does Father think? - He refuses to talk about it.
我试图跟他说我的担忧时 他还斥责我
And when I try to tell him my worries, he snaps at me.
- 因为你不讲理  - 够了 弗洛丽亚
- Because you're being unreasonable. - That's enough, Flor.
伊洛蒂 我发誓我只想为你好
Elodie, I swear that I only want what's best for you.
我是不是打扰你们了?
Am I interrupting something?
没有
No.
只是...
Just...
姑娘之间的谈话
girl talk.
明天是个大日子 姑娘们也该休息了
Well, tomorrow's a big day, and these girls, they need their rest.
想想我说的话 还有时间
Think about what I said. There's still time.
有时间做什么?
Time for what?
但愿你清楚自己在干什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
晚安 宝贝女儿
Good night, my angels.
- 晚安 父亲  - 晚安 父亲
- Good night, Father. - Good night, Father.
晚安
Good night.
哇
Wow.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
这是我王儿和新女儿伊洛蒂 奥瑞亚王妃
I present my son and new daughter, Elodie, Princess of Aurea.
再见 父亲
Goodbye, Father.
我希望有朝一日 我能有你今天一半美丽
I hope I'm half as beautiful someday as you are today.
你会比我还美一倍
Twice as beautiful.
- 我爱你  - 我爱你
- I love you. - I love you.
嘿!
Hey! Hey, hey!
我们要去哪里?
Where are we going?
还记得我跟你说过 在山上举行的古老仪式吗?
Remember I told you about those ancient ceremonies up on the mountain?
记得
Yes.
我们要去向祖先致敬
We're going to pay homage to my ancestors.
欢迎 王妃
Welcome, Princess.
几代人以来 我们的任务和职责
For generations, it has been our task, our duty,
就是保护我们的子民
to protect our people.
代价高昂 但是回报也很丰厚
The price is dear, but so too the reward.
所以今晚
So, tonight,
你将会加入一众女人 她们曾帮助建立这个王国
you join a long line of women who have helped to build this kingdom.
当我们的祖先第一次占有这片土地时
When our ancestors first lay claim to this island,
他们发现这里还有其他居民
they found they were not its sole inhabitants.
先前就有一个生物居住在此
A creature dwelt here first.
它的族类只剩它一个了
The last of its kind.
这头野兽野蛮嗜血
With savage bloodlust,
它会离开巢穴 袭击村庄
the beast left its lair and set upon the village.
于是国王召集士兵为他的子民报仇
So the king gathered his soldiers to avenge his people.
但他们的钢铁武器 根本不是怪兽的对手
But their steel was no match for the monster,
每个人都丧生了
and each man met his end.
除了一个人
Each save one.
对于国王 那头野兽给他安排了更残酷的命运
For the king, the beast had a far worse fate in store.
要他交出三个爱女 野兽才愿意把这座岛与人类共享
Give up his three beloved daughters and the island could be shared.
这是残酷的折磨
A cruel torture.
他深爱女儿们
He adored his daughters,
但是他对臣民的责任更大
but his duty to his subjects was stronger.
于是他们达成了契约
And so, a pact was made.
三位公主都葬身于野兽的肚子里
The three princesses met their end in the belly of the beast,
于是一个王国诞生了
and a kingdom was born.
我们每一代人都要纪念这次牺牲
It is this sacrifice we commemorate every generation.
这个传统能追溯到几世纪以前
A tradition going back centuries.
伸出手 孩子
Your hand, child.
你将继承这份荣誉和责任 奥瑞亚的伊洛蒂王妃
A legacy of honor and duty you now inherit, Princess Elodie of Aurea.
让我们两支血脉相连 快速合二为一
Let our two lines mingle and fast become one.
现在她流淌着皇室的血
She is now of royal blood.
为了确保我们的王国永远繁荣昌盛
To ensure that our kingdom thrives forevermore,
为王国尽一份力吧
pay your due to the realm.
把钱币扔进山沟里
Toss the coin into the chasm.
仪式到此结束
The ceremony is now complete.
你们可以返回了
You may make your return.
我得抱你回去
I'm supposed to carry you back.
其实我可以自己走
I'm fine with walking, really.
弗洛丽亚肯定会喜欢这个环节
Floria would love this part.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
有我抱着你呢
I've got you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不!
No!
救救我!
Help me!
救命!
Help!
有人吗?
Is anyone there?!
那不是我的
That's not mine.
我是祭祀品
I am the sacrifice. I am the sacrifice?
可怜的东西
You poor thing.
你这是怎么了?
What happened to you?
给予我力量吧 母亲
Give me strength, Mother.
母亲?
Mother?
你叫什么名字 小鸟儿?
Your name, little bird?
说出你的名字
Speak your name.
伊洛蒂
Elodie.
El-o-die.
真有意思
Exciting.
你想怎么样?
What do you want?
我想...按约定行事
I want... what is promised.
欠债要还
What is owed.
世世代代 你们族类都必须偿还
Every generation, your kind must pay.
我的族类?
My kind?
皇室的气味暴露了你
The scent of royalty betrays you.
是从你血液里散发出来的
It's in your blood.
接下来 是我最喜欢的环节
Now, my favorite part.
跑吧
Run.
我弄疼你了吗?
Did I hurt you?
现在不出声了?
Quiet now?
这个真聪明
A clever one.
上一个女孩一下就完蛋了
The last one was over so quick.
不
No.
母亲会希望你去拼一把
Mother wanted you to fight.
不要
No. No.
他是王子
He is a prince.
他们得相互熟悉一下
They must get to know each other.
我最大的愿望是去周游世界
My greatest wish is to go see the world.
或许有一天我们可以一起去
Perhaps, one day we will.
多亏了衣服
One for the dress.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不会伤害你的
I won't hurt you.
差点就抓到你了 小鸟儿
Almost caught you, little bird.
你躲起来了 跟所有其他女孩一样
You hide now, like all the others.
这里安全 她够不着❫
维❫
这没什么用
It makes no difference.
故事的结局总是一样的
This story always ends the same.
维
V.
维多利亚
Victoria.
碧翠丝
Beatrice.
阿尔忒弥斯
Artemis.
吉纳维芙
Genevive.
法蒂玛
Fatima.
卡洛塔
Carlotta.
有多少人?
How many?
有人逃出去过吗?
Did anyone make it out?
求你了 不要
Please, don't.
来人...
Somebody...
维多利亚❫
这是谎言
It's a lie.
走开
Get off.
我非常抱歉
I'm deeply sorry...
低估了你们
for underestimating you.
一张地图
A map.
现在我在哪里?
Now, where am I?
一棵树
A tree.
入口山洞
The entrance cave.
一直通往小鸟山洞
Following down into the bird cave.
经过曲折的隧道...
Through the twisted tunnel...
来到水边
reaching water.
萤光虫山洞
The glowworm cave.
继续往下走
Keep following down.
安全区❫
我在这里
I am here.
我要怎么逃出去?
How do I escape?
就是这里吗?
Is this it?
有王妃逃出去过吗?
Did a princess make it out?
三条路 走中间的岔路
Three ways. Take the middle fork.
音符
Music note.
水晶
Crystals.
继续走
Go on.
然后...我就自由了
And then... I am free.
伊洛蒂❫
中间岔路
The middle fork.
音乐
Music.
水晶
Crystals.
就是这里
This is it.
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
维❫
你逃出去了
You made it out.
不!
No!
伊洛蒂
Elodie.
飞吧 小鸟儿
Fly, little bird.
你好
Hello.
你好!
Hello!
我在这里! 救命!
I'm here! Help!
救命!
Help!
听到吗?
Hello!
这里无路可逃 公主
There is no way out, Princess.
不安全❫
你们谁也别想逃
Not for any of you.
三只被残杀了
Three were taken.
那就必须献祭三个
Three must be given.
伊洛蒂!
Elodie!
什么情况?
What's this?
伊洛蒂!
Elodie!
继续走
Move on.
大人 您付的钱只够带路到这里 我去上面等着
I've done what you paid for, milord. I'll just wait up top.
你不能这样做
You'll do no such thing.
我雇你来带我们去找她
I hired you to guide us to her.
没找到我的女儿 谁也别走
No one leaves here without my daughter.
伊洛蒂!
Elodie!
先前就有一个生物居住在此
A creature dwelt here first.
它的族类只剩它一个了
The last of its kind.
这是谎言
It's a lie.
"三只被残杀了"
Three taken.
杀死这些邪恶的幼崽
Slay the vile young.
排成一行!
Form the line!
求你了 饶了我吧
Please, spare me.
饶我一命
Show mercy.
我愿意给你任何东西
I will give you anything.
死亡还不足以惩罚你
Death is not enough for you.
你将会感受我的痛苦
You will know my pain.
伊洛蒂!
Elodie!
小声点 她会听见的
Be quiet. She can hear you.
我警告过您 您来得太晚了 那头野兽潜伏在巢穴中
I warned you. It's too late. The beast lurks in its lair.
- 它肯定早就抓她去那里狼吞...  - 巢穴在哪里?
- It's surely taken her there to devour-- - This lair. Where is it?
大人 您女儿在这里待得太久了
Sir, your daughter's been down here nigh on too long.
几乎可以肯定她被杀了
She's almost certainly been killed.
伊洛蒂!
Elodie!
据说有人曾经试图猎杀那头野兽
I'm told some have tried to hunt the beast.
想取它的血
For its blood.
胡说
Nonsense.
你为什么来这里?
Why are you here?
我是来找我女儿的
I'm here for my daughter.
父亲
Father.
求你了
Please.
我求求你
I beg of you.
你应该求的不是我
It's not my mercy that you should seek.
叫她来
Call her.
她还活着?
She's alive?
伊洛蒂还活着?
Elodie's still alive?
我闻到了她的气味
I smell her.
她躲起来了
Hiding.
她在暗中观察
Watching.
叫她来
Call her.
不
No.
叫她来
Call her.
伊洛蒂
Elodie.
你能听见吗?
Can you hear me?
我犯了一个可怕的错
I have... I have made a horrible, horrible mistake.
牺牲了我最心爱的宝贝
To sacrifice the one thing I love most.
用你的命来换
To trade your life
我子民的美好生活
for the good of my people.
我以为我能拿着金子走
I thought that I could take the gold.
心安理得地活下去
That I could live with myself.
这是我选的
My choice.
但是我做不到
But I can't.
我做不到
I can't.
叫她过来找你
Tell her to come to you.
最后一次机会
Last chance.
伊洛蒂 听我说
Elodie. Hear me.
我是你的父亲 你要听我的话
I am your father. You will obey me.
我命令你
I order you.
不要出来!
Do not come out!
不
No.
不!
No!
伊洛蒂
Ellie.
用绳索
Use the ropes.
你的继母和弗洛丽亚
Your stepmother and Floria,
她们在船上等你
they wait for you at the ship.
原谅我
Forgive me.
快走!
Go! Go! Go!
走吧
Go.
那个该死的女孩 我就知道她会惹事
That damn girl. I knew she was trouble.
- 你要去哪?  - 去解决问题
- Where are you going? - To fix this.
- 住手  - 后退
- Stop. - Stand back.
伊洛蒂
Elodie.
快开门!
Open up!
让开!
Get out of the way!
出来!
Get out!
抓住她
Seize her.
不可以!
You can't!
- 不行! 她只是个孩子!  - 不要!
- No! She's just a child! - No!
你许诺过给我们一个女儿
You promised us a daughter.
- 继母!  - 不!
- Stepmother! - No!
弗洛丽亚!
Floria!
伊洛蒂
Elodie.
继母
Stepmother.
- 伊洛蒂  - 继母
- Elodie. - Stepmother.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我还行
I can manage.
弗洛丽亚呢?
Where's Floria?
他们抓她去替代你当祭祀品了
They took her to the caves in your place.
我想阻拦 但你妹妹还是被带走了
I tried to stop them from taking your sister.
我必须去救她
I have to save her.
不 我去 我可以找到她
No, I'll go. I can find her.
或许已经太晚了
It may be too late.
不会
No.
有我帮忙就不会
Not if I can help it.
你父亲...
Your father...
去吧
Go.
拜托 放我走!
Please. Let me go!
请让我走吧
Please let me go.
不 别这样
No, don't do this.
母亲 够了! 她太年轻了
Mother, enough! She's too young.
王子要保护王国 不能有丝毫犹豫或怨言
A prince protects his kingdom, without hesitation or complaint.
伸出手
Give me your hand.
我做不到 她还是个小孩
I cannot do this. She's just a child.
你太懦弱了
You're weak.
不! 请不要这样对我!
No! Please don't do this to me!
放开我!
Get off of me!
放手! 放开我!
Let go! Off of me!
扔她进去
Throw her in.
弗洛丽亚!
Floria!
我来救你 弗洛丽亚
I'm coming for you, Flor.
我的小宝贝们...
My little ones...
他们不让你们活命
They did not let you live.
我也不会让伊洛蒂活命
Nor shall I let Elodie.
你姐姐会来救你的
Your sister will come for you.
她来了
There she is now.
嘿 弗洛丽亚 听得见吗?
Hello, Floria. Floria, can you hear me?
醒醒!
Wake up!
我们得快点
We need to hurry.
弗洛丽亚!
Floria!
伊洛蒂
Ellie.
伊洛蒂 你还活着
Elodie, you're alive.
好了 我要带你出去
Okay. I'm going to get you out of here.
我的腿 掉下来的时候摔伤了
My leg. I hurt it when I fell.
没时间了 弗洛丽亚
We don't have time, Flor.
不 别这么快回来
No, no, no. Not yet.
现在怎么办?
What now?
你得赶快躲起来
You have to hide quickly.
那你呢?
What about you?
我必须告诉她真相
I must tell her the truth.
来吧
Come on.
你们躲哪去了?
Where are you hiding?
恶龙
Dragon.
这杀不死我
That won't kill me,
但会激怒我
but it will make me angry.
很好
Good.
我也很愤怒
I'm angry too.
我们俩都被欺骗了
We have both been lied to.
他们说你攻击了村庄
They said you set upon their village.
说国王来这里只是为了保卫子民
That the king came only to defend his people.
我没惹过他 他就来了
He came unprovoked.
我知道他们做了什么
I know what they did.
我知道他们杀了你的孩子
I know they killed your children.
"他们"? 就是你们!
"They"? You!
你的族类 你的血脉
Your kind, your blood.
不是!
No!
我的女儿们是我最后的血脉
My daughters were the last of my line.
所以 直到我咽气之前 我也要夺走他们的女儿
So, I will take their daughters until my final breath.
但你并没有做到 我们不是他们的女儿
Except you haven't. We are not their daughters.
还撒谎
More lies.
伊洛蒂!
Ellie!
现在 你就要知道我女儿们的痛苦了
Now, you will know my daughters' pain.
我跟他们不是一伙的!
I am not one of them!
我闻到了你血液里的气味
I smell it in your blood.
伊洛蒂
El-o-die.
接受你的命运吧...
Accept your fate...
就像我接受命运一样
as I have mine.
我们都要孤独死去
We are to die alone.
不
No.
我身边有一支军队
I have an army with me.
在这下面被夺走生命的每个无辜女人
Every innocent woman whose life was stolen down here.
你们的族类绝不无辜
Your kind were never innocent.
那就来吧
Then go ahead.
释放你的烈焰
Show me your fire.
怎么?
Well?
你还在等什么?
What are you waiting for?
喷火烧我吧
Burn me.
喷火烧我呀!
Burn me!
我的妹妹也有这个
My sister had this too.
我们都有
All of us did.
他们用这个方法 让我们成为皇室成员
That is how they make us royal.
这就是你闻到的血腥味
That is the blood you smell.
他们欺骗了你
They fooled you.
你一直在残杀无辜的女儿 就像皇室残杀幼龙一样
You've been killing innocent daughters just like they did.
那就来个了结吧
Then, end it.
不
No.
我再也不想听命于别人了
I'm through doing what I'm told.
伊洛蒂
Elodie.
你得相信我 在那之后 我片刻都睡不着...
You must believe me. I haven't slept a moment since--
在你试图杀死我妹妹之后?
Since you tried to kill my sister?
我别无选择
I had no choice.
不准你向这个平民...
Don't you dare explain yourself to this...
多做解释
this commoner.
她是要当第三个吗?
Is she to be the third?
三号王妃
Princess number three.
她是最后一个了 然后我就可以自由迎娶任何...
She's the last, and then I'll be free to marry whoever I--
别说了 亨利
That's enough, Henry.
你对我们忍受的痛苦一无所知
You know nothing of what we've endured.
你完全不了解我们的故事
You know nothing of our story.
带上你的家人
Take your family
然后跑吧
and run.
来 我们走
Come. Let's go.
我给你们最后一次逃走的机会
I will offer you all one last chance to do the same.
不走?
No?
你这个傲慢的东西
You insolent creature.
你以为我们现在应该怕你吗?
You think we ought to fear you now?
为什么?
Why?
因为你设法逃过了恶龙的魔爪?
Because you somehow managed to escape the dragon?
你们应该害怕的不是我
It's not me you should fear.
你们的故事至此就要终结了
This is the end of your story.
快跑!
Run!
- 恶龙来了!  - 跑!
- It's the dragon! - Run!
不!
No!
谁来帮我搬这个桶
Someone give me a hand with this barrel.
都放聪明一点 伙计们
Let's be sharp there, lads.
开玩笑的吧?
You can't be serious.
我没开玩笑
But I am.
我们一起经营它
We'll run it together.
我们有丰富的物资供应
We've got a bounty of supplies.
足以让我们度过这次和下一个寒冬
Enough to get us through this freeze and the next.
哦 伊洛蒂
Oh, Elodie.
我只信赖你能照看好 我们的子民 母亲
You're the only person I trust to look after our people, Mother.
我也能帮忙吗?
Can I help too?
弗洛丽亚
Floria.
我也指望你啦
I'm counting on it.
继母 你快来看看这个
Stepmother. Stepmother, come and see this.
天哪
Oh, wide heavens!
小姐 我们要去哪?
My lady, what course shall we steer?
回家
Home.
翻译:杨宇航